{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The disorder in which of the following may cause \"Ehlers-Danlos Syndrome\"?", "opta": "Dlashin protein", "optb": "Collagen protein", "optc": "Fibrin protein", "optd": "Globulin protein", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the protein is involved in Alzheimer's disease?", "opta": "A4", "optb": "Amylin", "optc": "Fibrin", "optd": "Alzhemin", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If the RBC of human were kept in 0.9% NaCl solution, what sort of change will occur to RBC?", "opta": "Cell will Burst", "optb": "Cell will shrink", "optc": "No change to RBC", "optd": "RBC will destroy", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the modification in hemoglobin is the cause of sickle cell anemia?", "opta": "A mutation in the beta chain", "optb": "A deletion in the beta chain", "optc": "Replacement of the B chain by D chain", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Klinefelter syndrome is a manifestation of which chromosome aneuploidy?", "opta": "XXX", "optb": "XYY", "optc": "XXY", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "During sickle cell anemia which of the following takes place?", "opta": "Glutamine change to valine", "optb": "Valine change to glutamine", "optc": "Aspartic acid change to glutamic acid", "optd": "Glutamic acid change to aspartic acid", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Methotrexate is toxic to human cells because it inhibits", "opta": "formation of CTP from UTP", "optb": "reduction of H2 folate to H4 folate", "optc": "synthesis of PRPP", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the defective enzyme in the glycogen storage Von Gierke's disease?", "opta": "Phosphorylase", "optb": "Phosphofructokinase", "optc": "Glucose-6-phosphatase", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A deficiency of the enzyme Hypoxanthine Guanine phosphoribosyl transferase (HGPRT) may cause", "opta": "Gaucher's disease", "optb": "Ehlers-Danlos syndrome", "optc": "Lesch- Nyhan syndrome", "optd": "Kleinefelter's syndrome", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following sets belongs to a distinct class or category?", "opta": "Ribose, sucrose, glucose, fructose", "optb": "Sterols, waxes, fatty acids, amino acids.", "optc": "Oils, sterols, waxes, fats", "optd": "Nucleotide, nucleoside, nucleus, DNA", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}